Rebecca West Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1914-75; Series I; 11; (27 boxes)
  - REBECCA WEST CORRESPONDENCE
    - Towerton, Miss, 1969 Jun 25 (Box 17, Folder 835)
    - Tracy, Honor, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 836)
    - Trefusis, Violet, 1955-64, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 837)
    - Trilling, Diana, 1956-68 (Box 17, Folder 838)
    - Trilling, Lionel, 1952 Jun 17 (Box 17, Folder 839)
    - Trotter, Philip, 1955 May 19 (Box 17, Folder 840)
    - Troy, William, 1930 Jan 20 (Box 17, Folder 841)
    - Turnbull, Andrew, 1965 Jan 3 (Box 17, Folder 842)
    - Tyson, Mrs., 1956 Aug 30 (Box 17, Folder 843)
    - "U" general, 1944-51 (Box 17, Folder 844)
    - Union of Democratic Control, 1939-41 (Box 17, Folder 845)
    - University of Chicago Law Review, 1950-51 (Box 17, Folder 846)
    - "V" general, 1953-66 (Box 17, Folder 847)
    - Vachall, Horace Annerley, 1934 Jan 25 (Box 17, Folder 848)
    - Vance, Wilson, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 849)
    - Vanderpump, Frank, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 850)
    - Van Doren, Irita, 1949-50 (Box 17, Folder 851)
    - Van Druten, John, 1928-57, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 852-53)
    - Vanity Fair, 1933 Dec 12 (Box 17, Folder 854)
    - Vanne, Marda, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 855)
    - Vansittart, Sarita, Lady, 1958-70 (Box 17, Folder 856)
    - Vaughan, Constance, 1922 Dec 4 (Box 17, Folder 857)
    - Vaughan, Edie, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 858)
    - Vermehren, Petra, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 859)
    - Vernon, Emilie, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 860)
    - Vernon (?), Marjorie, 1959 Jan 22 (Box 17, Folder 861)
    - Vernon, Virginia, 1938-68 (Box 17, Folder 862)
    - Victor-Evans, Katherine, 1969 May 1 (Box 17, Folder 863)
    - Victor-Gollancz, Ltd., 1950-56 (Box 17, Folder 864)
    - The Viking Press, 1929-39 (Box 17, Folder 865)
      See also: Ben Huebsch, Box 10, folder 404
    - Vinaver, Stanislov, 1936-69 (Box 17, Folder 866)
      See also: Box 27, folder 1208
    - Virginia Law Review, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 867)
    - Vogue, 1955, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 868)
    - Voice of Canadian Serbs, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 869)
    - Voight, Frederick, 1945-46 (Box 17, Folder 870)
    - Volk, Karen, 1967 Apr 24 (Box 17, Folder 871)
    - "W" general, 1936-69 (Box 17, Folder 872)
    - W. W. Norton & Company, Inc., 1954 Feb 10 (Box 17, Folder 872a)
    - Wakefield, Gilbert E., 1960 (Box 17, Folder 873)
    - Waldman, Milton, 1958, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 874)
    - Walker, Andrew, 1930 Nov 2 (Box 17, Folder 875)
    - Wallace, Doreen, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 876)
    - Walmsay, L. W., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 877)
    - Walpole, Hugh, 1928 Sep 26 (Box 17, Folder 878)
    - Waley, Arthur, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 879)
    - Walston, Harry, Lord, 1947-70 (Box 17, Folder 880)
    - Warendorf, J. C. S., 1966, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 881)
    - Waring, Clelia, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 882)
    - Waring, L. F., 1944-45 (Box 17, Folder 883)
    - Warner, Rex, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 884)
    - Warr, Gillian, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 885)
    - Watson, Graham, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 886)
    - Watson, Vera, 1958-69 (Box 17, Folder 887)
    - Watson, Miss, 1942-44 (Box 17, Folder 888)
    - Watt, Ian, 1959 May 18 (Box 17, Folder 889)
    - Watts, Marjorie, 1965-67 (Box 17, Folder 890)
    - Waugh, Alec, 1952, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 891)
    - Webster, Margaret, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 892)
    - Webster, Mary Morison, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 893)
    - Wedgwood, C. V. (Cecily Veronica), 1958-65 (Box 18, Folder 894)
    - Weedon, Peter Weedon, Wendy, 1969 Apr 23 (Box 18, Folder 895)
    - Weekley, Montague, 1969-70 (Box 18, Folder 896)
    - Weeks, Edward, 1958 Sep 2 (Box 18, Folder 897)
      See also: Atlantic Monthly, Box 5, folder 102
    - Weichlein, Hugo M., 1963-65 (Box 18, Folder 898)
    - Weintraub, Stanley, 1961-67 (Box 18, Folder 899)
    - Weissberger, L. Arnold, 1956 Feb 28 (Box 18, Folder 900)
    - Weissel, J. M., 1969 (Box 18, Folder 901)
    - Weissel, Maria, 1939 Dec 10 (Box 18, Folder 902)
    - Wellington, Amy, 1915 Jan 8 (Box 18, Folder 903)
    - Wells, G. P., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 904)
    - Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1913-14 (Box 18, Folder 905-22)
    - Wells, H. G., 1914-15 (Box 19, Folder 923-42)
    - Wells, H. G., 1916-19 (Box 20, Folder 943-61)
    - Wells, H. G., 1920-23 (Box 21, Folder 962-75)
    - Wells, H. G., 1924-44, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 975a-l)
    - Wells, Marjorie, 1946-56 (Box 22, Folder 976)
    - Wertheimer-Bing, Ilka, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 977)
    - Westcott, Glenway, 1966, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 978)
    - West, Anthony, 1944-67 (Box 22, Folder 979-81)
    - West, Kitty, 1951-58, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 982-85)
    - Westminster Bank Limited, 1955-56 (Box 22, Folder 986)
    - Weston, Selwyn, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 987)
    - Whistler, Laurence, 1958-65 (Box 22, Folder 988)
    - Whitaker, Margaret, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 989)
    - Whitby, Stafford, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 990)
    - White, Antonia, 1962 May 28 (Box 22, Folder 991)
    - White, Katherine (Mrs. E. B. White), 1960 (Box 22, Folder 992)
    - Whitehill, Walter Muir, 1968 Dec 4 (Box 22, Folder 993)
    - Whitney, Adrianne, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 994)
    - Wicks, H. W., 1946-64 (Box 22, Folder 995)
    - Widner, Alice, 1959-60 (Box 22, Folder 996)
    - Wienberger, Arnold, 1953 Jan 15 (Box 22, Folder 997)
    - Wilczynski, Katerina, 1963-69 (Box 22, Folder 998)
    - Wilenski, Marjorie Wilenski, R. H., 1959-69 (Box 22, Folder 999)
    - Wilet, Keltini, 1961 Feb 17 (Box 22, Folder 1000)
    - Wilkinson, Ellen, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 1001)
    - Willes, Peter, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 1002)
    - William Hodge & Co., Ltd., 1949 (Box 22, Folder 1003)
    - Williams, E., Mrs., 1961 Sep 18 (Box 22, Folder 1004)
    - Williams, Emlyn, 1967 Jul 3 (Box 22, Folder 1005)
    - Williams-Ellis, Anabel, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 1006)
    - Willis, Peter, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 1007)
    - Willkie, Wendell (with related documents), 1941-42 (Box 22, Folder 1008)
      See also: Box 14, folder 650
    - Wilshire, Logan, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 1009)
    - Wilshire, Mary, 1928-29 (Box 22, Folder 1010)
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1930-42 (Box 22, Folder 1011)
    - Winks, Robin W., 1965 (Box 22, Folder 1012)
    - Winn, Godfrey, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 1013)
    - Winnicraft, Eileen ("Martha Blount"), 1942 (Box 22, Folder 1014)
    - Wiskemann, Elizabeth, 1959-69 (Box 22, Folder 1015)
    - Wolf, Bessie, 1965 Apr 8 (Box 22, Folder 1016)
    - Wolf, Constance Wolf, Alfred L., 1963-66, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 1017)
    - Wolfe, Glenn, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 1018)
    - Wolfson, Victor, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 1019)
    - Wolstenholme, Adelaide, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 1020)
    - Women's Affairs Section (Hamburg), 1949 (Box 22, Folder 1021)
    - Woman's Journal, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 1022)
    - Women's Press Club of London, Ltd., 1969 Dec 11 (Box 22, Folder 1023)
    - Wood, Betty O., 1968 (Box 22, Folder 1024)
    - Wood, Greta (with related letters), 1938-39 (Box 22, Folder 1025)
    - Woodruff, Douglas Woodruff, Mia, 1948-67 (Box 22, Folder 1026)
    - Woolf, Virginia, 1931, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 1027)
    - Woollcott, Alexander, 1930-39 (Box 22, Folder 1028)
    - World Publishing Company, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 1029)
    - Wright, M., Miss, 1938-39 (Box 23, Folder 1030)
    - Wright, Thew Wright, Kit, 1962-70 (Box 23, Folder 1031)
    - Wright, Lady, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 1032)
    - Wright & Webb, 1962 Apr 25 (Box 23, Folder 1033)
    - Wyatt, Woodrow, 1958-1959 (Box 23, Folder 1034)
    - "Y" general, 1946-60 (Box 23, Folder 1035)
    - Yale Review, 1933 Sep 16 (Box 23, Folder 1036)
    - Yale University, 1970, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 1037)
    - Yevlich, Pavel, 1943 Jul 26 (Box 23, Folder 1038)
    - Yovanovitch, Slobodan, 1941-46 (Box 23, Folder 1039)
    - Young Elizabethan, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 1040)
    - Yugoslav Relief Society (with related correspondence), 1943-47 (Box 23, Folder 1041)
    - The Yugoslav Red Cross Society, 1941-45 (Box 23, Folder 1042)
    - The Yugoslav Society of Great Britain (with related correspondence), 1941-45 (Box 23, Folder 1043)
    - "Z" general, 1968-69, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 1044)
    - Zeman, Z. A. B., 1968-69 (Box 23, Folder 1045)
    - Wedding telegrams, 1930 (Box 23, Folder 1046)
    - Unidentified, 1930-69 (Box 23, Folder 1047-51)
  - HENRY ANDREWS CORRESPONDENCE
    - Alsop, Joseph, 1949 Dec 20 (Box 24, Folder 1052)
    - Anderson, C. M., 1948 Jun 14 (Box 24, Folder 1053)
    - Anderson, Herbert F. (Box 24, Folder 1054)
    - Andrews, Ernest, 1911-36 (Box 24, Folder 1055-62)
    - Andrews, Hertha, 1949, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 1063)
    - Andrews, Louis, 1949 Apr 2 (Box 24, Folder 1064)
    - Andrews, Mary (with related correspondence), 1917-31 (Box 24, Folder 1065)
    - Astor, David, 1949 Apr 14 (Box 24, Folder 1066)
    - Andrée, 1948 Mar 5 (Box 24, Folder 1067)
    - Barclays Bank, Ltd., 1937-55 (Box 24, Folder 1068)
    - Barlow, Robert, 1954-57 (Box 24, Folder 1069)
    - Beerensson, Miss, 1949 Mar 9 (Box 24, Folder 1070)
    - Behrman, S. N., 1966 (Box 24, Folder 1071)
    - Berenson, Bernard, 1953-56 (Box 24, Folder 1072)
    - Berenson, Nicky, 1954-56 (Box 24, Folder 1073)
    - Berry, H. Vaughan, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 1074)
    - Binyon, Laurence, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 1075)
    - B'nai B'rith (J. H. Taylor), 1938 (Box 24, Folder 1076)
    - Bishop, W. H. A., 1949 (Box 24, Folder 1077)
    - Blumenfeld, Erik, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 1078)
    - Box, Dr., 1949 Dec 4 (Box 24, Folder 1079)
    - Brinkmann, Mr., 1949 Mar 5 (Box 24, Folder 1080)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1949-50 (Box 24, Folder 1081)
    - British European Airways, 1949 Jun 24 (Box 24, Folder 1082)
    - Bucks Free Press, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 1083)
    - Chief of Counsel for War Crimes, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 1084)
    - Colefax, Sybil, Lady, 1942, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 1085)
    - [Columbus documents], 1951-59, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 1086-92)
    - Connolly, Cyril, 1960 Mar 13 (Box 24, Folder 1093)
    - The Contemporary Review, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 1094)
    - The Daily Mail, 1949 Aug 5 (Box 24, Folder 1095)
    - DeMille, Agnes (Prude), 1964-68 (Box 24, Folder 1096)
    - Die Zeit, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 1097)
    - Dressel, Alfred, 1938-72 (Box 24, Folder 1098)
    - Dulles, Allen, 1937-69 (Box 24, Folder 1099)
    - Dunlop, J. K. (with related correspondence), 1949 (Box 24, Folder 1100)
    - Einstein, Lewis, 1915-70 (Box 25, Folder 1101-16)
    - Elias, Fritz, 1929 (Box 26, Folder 1117)
    - Foreign Office (German Section), 1949 (Box 26, Folder 1118)
    - Foster, Mr., 1949 Nov 5 (Box 26, Folder 1119)
    - Freeman, H. W., 1949 (Box 26, Folder 1120)
    - Gauntlett, G. R., 1949 (Box 26, Folder 1121)
    - Gavrilovic, Kosara, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 1122)
    - German Emergency Committee, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 1123)
    - Gibbs, G. C., 1949 Sep 3 (Box 26, Folder 1124)
    - Gillett, A. B., 1949 Dec 12 (Box 26, Folder 1125)
    - Goodenough, William, 1949 Sep 4 (Box 26, Folder 1126)
    - Goodheart, Arthur, 1949-66 (Box 26, Folder 1127)
    - Gregory, Rowcliffe, and Company, 1950-68 (Box 26, Folder 1128-32)
    - Grisebaum, Gustav von, 1938 Nov 27 (Box 26, Folder 1133)
    - Harper, C. J., Col., 1949 Sep 19 (Box 26, Folder 1134)
    - Harrod, Roy Forbes, Sir, 1928-59 (Box 26, Folder 1135)
    - Heglage, Jan, 1915 (Box 26, Folder 1136)
    - Herms Bank, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 1137)
    - Horrocks, Brian, 1952 Dec 23 (Box 26, Folder 1138)
    - Hughes, G. E., 1948-49 (Box 26, Folder 1139)
    - Hutchinson, George Evelyn, 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 1140)
    - Ingrams, Leonard, 1948 Sep 22 (Box 26, Folder 1141)
    - Jacobi, Oliver, 1932 Oct 10 (Box 26, Folder 1142)
    - Jewkes, John, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1143)
    - Jones, Enid Bagnold, 1938-39 (Box 26, Folder 1144)
    - Joseph, H. W. B., 1924 Jul 1 (Box 26, Folder 1145)
    - Kaufmann, Erich, 1948 Jul 18 (Box 26, Folder 1146)
    - Kehl, W., 1931 (Box 26, Folder 1147)
    - Kgl. Norsk General Konsulat, 1938 (Box 26, Folder 1148)
    - Kirkpatrick, Ivone, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 1149)
    - Kordt, Erich, 1949 Jun 9 (Box 26, Folder 1150)
    - Kuenheim, Yvonne (with related correspondence), 1949 (Box 26, Folder 1151)
    - Kutiak, P. V., 1948 (Box 26, Folder 1152)
    - Landesregierung Schleswig-Holstein (with related correspondence), 1945 (Box 26, Folder 1153)
    - Landwirtschaftliche Forschungsantalt (Braunschwerg-Volkenrode), 1948-49 (Box 26, Folder 1154)
    - Laski, Harold Joseph, 1946 May 2 (Box 26, Folder 1155)
    - Lavine, Irene A. Lavine, John, 1956-67 (Box 26, Folder 1156-59)
    - Levin, Bernard, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 1160)
    - Liston, D. J., 1949 Oct. 5 (Box 26, Folder 1161)
    - Lumley, S. H., 1949 (Box 26, Folder 1162)
    - MacLeod, Norman, 1939-43 (Box 26, Folder 1163)
    - MacMillan, Harold, 1938-39 (Box 26, Folder 1164)
    - Macready, Gordon N., Sir, 1948-49 (Box 26, Folder 1165)
    - Marcus, H. H. (with related correspondence), 1947-48 (Box 26, Folder 1166)
    - Marshall, Thomas, 1945 Nov 5 (Box 26, Folder 1167)
    - Masaryk, Jan, 1943-44 (Box 26, Folder 1168)
    - Mays-Smith, R. S., 1948 (Box 26, Folder 1169)
    - Miksch, Dr., 1949 Apr 16 (Box 26, Folder 1170)
    - Murray, Gilbert, 1954 Feb 26 (Box 26, Folder 1171)
    - Murray, Mary, Lady, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 1172)
    - Namier, Mr., 1949 Apr 24 (Box 27, Folder 1173)
    - The New Statesman and Nation, 1953, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 1174)
    - New York Herald Tribune, 1949 Dec 31 (Box 27, Folder 1175)
    - Nippold, Z. H., 1949 May 2 (Box 27, Folder 1176)
    - The Observer (London), 1949 Dec 10 (Box 27, Folder 1177)
    - Ogilvie, F. W., 1939 Aug 26 (Box 27, Folder 1178)
    - Pabsch, Frank, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 1179)
    - Pakenham, Lord, 1948 May 28 (Box 27, Folder 1180)
    - Picture Post, 1949 (Box 27, Folder 1181)
    - Pinsent, Gerald H. S., 1941 (Box 27, Folder 1182)
    - Plavich, J., 1948 May 12 (Box 27, Folder 1183)
    - Playfair, E. W., 1948 (Box 27, Folder 1184)
    - Powicke, J. M., 1937-39 (Box 27, Folder 1185)
    - Prichard, M., 1918 Sep 1 (Box 27, Folder 1186)
    - Ralston, Edna, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 1187)
    - Rebac, Anica Sevic (with related correspondence), 1937-38 (Box 27, Folder 1188)
    - Reizi, Sophie, 1936-37 (Box 27, Folder 1189-90)
    - Ropke, William, 1949 Sep 5 (Box 27, Folder 1191)
    - The Royal Empire Society, 1950 Feb 15 (Box 27, Folder 1192)
    - Salomon, Virginia, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 1193)
    - Saurat, D.
      See Anica Sevic Rebac
    - Schell, Josef, 1938-41 (Box 27, Folder 1194)
    - Schwabe, Walter, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 1195)
    - Seton-Watson, R. W. (Robert William), 1937-39 (Box 27, Folder 1196)
    - Simpkin Marshall, Ltd., 1949 Apr 16 (Box 27, Folder 1197)
    - Smithers, W., 1949 (Box 27, Folder 1198)
    - The Spectator, 1942 (Box 27, Folder 1199)
    - Stewart, Major General, 1949 May 7 (Box 27, Folder 1200)
    - Strachey, John, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 1201)
    - Sun Life Assurance Company of Canada, 1950 (Box 27, Folder 1202)
    - Taylor, Alan, 1942-45 (Box 27, Folder 1203)
    - Thompson, Allan R., n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1204)
    - Time and Tide, 1949-51 (Box 27, Folder 1205)
    - The Times (London), 1948-50 (Box 27, Folder 1206)
    - Under Secretary of State (Home Office), 1938 (Box 27, Folder 1207)
    - Vinaver, Stanislav, 1937 Jun 11 (Box 27, Folder 1208)
    - Walter, A. E. M., Brigadier, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 1209)
    - Weil, Herbert, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 1210)
    - Weir, Cecil, 1948-49 (Box 27, Folder 1211)
    - West, Anthony West, Kitty, 1949, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1212)
    - Westminster Bank Limited, 1949 (Box 27, Folder 1213)
    - Whitmore, H., 1949 Mar 16 (Box 27, Folder 1214)
    - Wright, Lord, 1949 Jun 30 (Box 27, Folder 1215)
    - Zeverijn, S. W., 1937-39 (Box 27, Folder 1216)
    - Unidentified, 1914-49, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1217)
- Writings, Date: 1894-1973; Series II; 4.25; (10 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, is divided into Books and Shorter Works (essays, reviews, etc.) and is arranged alphabetically by title.
  - BOOKS
    - A la recherche du temps perdu
      (Translation by Rebecca West of Marcel Proust's Sodom and Gomorrha, incomplete. With review of Fivescore Years by G. G. Coulton, essays "Princess Elizabeth" and "Second Front", and outline of untitled play.)
      - Holograph notebook, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1218)
    - Black Lamb and Gray Falcon
      - Background material
        - "Diary of 2nd Yugoslavian Trip". Holograph notebook (Box 28, Folder 1219-20)
        - Other material, 1894, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1221)
      - Reviews, 1942 Feb 28 (Box 28, Folder 1222)
      - Miscellaneous, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 1223)
    - The Court and the Castle
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected (with holograph identification of references), n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1224-27)
      - Setting typescript, corrected, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 1228-33)
      - Setting typescript, corrected, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 1234-36)
      - Plate proofs
        See: Oversize Box 43, folder 1516
      - Page proofs (Marked "Duplicate Set")
        See: Oversize, Box 43, folders 1517-19
      - Page proofs, corrected
        See: Oversize, Box 43, folders 1520-22
      - Page proofs, revised
        See: Oversize, Box 43, folders 1523-25
    - Ending in Earnest
      - Holograph notebooks, [1931] (Box 29, Folder 1237-38)
    - The Fountain Overflows
      - Holograph manuscript (mixed drafts; incomplete), n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1239)
    - Harriet Hume
      - Holograph notebook (with drafts of stories "Lucky Boy" and "That Jewel Affair at Monte Carlo"), [1929] (Box 30, Folder 1240-41)
      - Holograph text
        See: Oversize, Box 44, folders 1526-27
      - Cover design (with related correspondence), 1952-55, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1242)
    - Letter to a Grandfather
      - Holograph notebook, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1243)
      - Reviews, 1933 (Box 30, Folder 1244)
    - The Meaning of Treason
      - Holograph draft A (notebook), n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1245-46)
      - Holograph draft B (notebook), n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1247)
      - Correspondence. B. O'Reilly lawsuit, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 1247a)
      - Deposition of James H. Barrett in B. O'Reilly lawsuit. Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1248)
      - Evelyn Waugh lawsuit. Newspaper clippings, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 1249)
      - Related correspondence. Holograph and typescript, 1956, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1250)
      - Reviews, 1947-49 (Box 30, Folder 1251)
    - The Return of the Soldier
      (Dramatization by John van Druten)
      - Typescript, carbon ("Adopted for broadcasting by Peggy Wells"), 1952 (Box 31, Folder 1252)
      - Letter to editor of The Observer, 1928 Jun 24 (Box 31, Folder 1253)
      - Reviews, 1928 (Box 31, Folder 1254-56)
    - Saint Augustine
      - Holograph draft (notebook), n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1257-58)
      - Text in French: typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1259)
      - Related material, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1260)
    - Strange Necessity
      - Holograph draft, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1261-62)
      - Reviews, 1928-29 (Box 31, Folder 1263-65)
    - The Thinking Reed
      - Holograph notebooks, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1266-68)
      - "Part of Thinking Reed under title The Maenad "Short Life of a Saint"): holograph notebook (Box 32, Folder 1269)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Stories
      - "The Addict": holograph and typescript (Box 33, Folder 1270)
      - "The Magician of Pell Street": holograph notebook, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1271)
      - "Life Sentence"
        See: Box 32, folder 1269
      - "Short Life of a Saint"
      - "There Is No Conversation"
        - Holograph notebook, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1272)
        - Nash's Magazine, 1929 Jun (Box 33, Folder 1273)
    - Essays and Articles
      - "The Amazing Mr. Stanley, Storyteller of the East." The Evening Standard (London), 1948 Dec 2 (Box 33, Folder 1274)
      - "America in Election Time." Sunday Times (London), 1928 Nov 18 (Box 33, Folder 1275)
      - "The American Novel." John O'London's Weekly, 1927 Feb 12 (Box 33, Folder 1276)
      - "The Anatomy of Writing." The Author, 1949 (Box 33, Folder 1277)
      - "Anti-Semitism in London." Evening Standard, 1947 Sep-Oct (Box 33, Folder 1278)
      - "Are You in Love With Life -- or Death?" Daily Herald, 1928 (Box 33, Folder 1279)
      - "Are Women Less Beautiful?" The Observer, 1920 Aug 1 (Box 33, Folder 1280)
      - "Assassination" (with "The Englishman Abroad," "I Believe," "Change and Cows," "The Organization of Buckingham Palace," "Humbug and The Resistance Movement," and untitled essay on Yugoslavia): holograph notebook (Box 33, Folder 1281)
      - "The Bachelor Girl." Royal Magazine, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1282)
      - [Bottomley]. Untitled article: proof sheets., n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1283)
      - "Capital Punishment." The New York Times, 1973 Apr 1 (Box 33, Folder 1284)
      - "Chinese Puzzle": typescript., n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1285)
      - "The Coming of Spring." The Listener, 1929 Apr 10 (Box 33, Folder 1286)
      - "A Commentary." The Bookman, 1929 Mar (Box 33, Folder 1287)
      - "A Commentary on Books and Things." Time and Tide., 1928 Dec 14 (Box 33, Folder 1288)
      - "A Commentary on Books and Things. The High Cost of Personal Journalism." Time and Tide, 1929 Jan 18 (Box 33, Folder 1289)
      - "The Craft of Reviewing." T. P.'s Weekly, 1928 Mar 31 (Box 33, Folder 1290)
      - [Democratic Convention]. Newspaper articles by Rebecca West, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 1291)
      - "Do the Jews Get More Than 'Fair Share'?" Evening Standard, 1947 Oct 20 (Box 33, Folder 1292)
      - "Eat Less Bread. Why We Must Ration Ourselves": newspaper clipping, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1293)
      - "The Englishman Abroad": holograph notebook (Box 33, Folder 1294)
        See also: Box 33, folder 1280
      - [Faith Brook in The Kidders ]: typescripts, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1295)
      - "The Flapper." The Royal Magazine, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1296)
      - "Fuchs Trial Focuses Problems of To-Day." Glasgow Herald, 1950 Mar 2 (Box 33, Folder 1297)
      - "The Function of the Weekly Review." Time and Tide, 1927 Dec 9 (Box 33, Folder 1298)
      - "General Dyer." Time and Tide, 1929 Apr 19 (Box 33, Folder 1299)
      - "Germany's Refugees: A Threat to the Stability of Europe.", 1949 Nov (Box 33, Folder 1300)
      - "Girls, Stick to Your Youth": newspaper clipping, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1301)
      - "The Good German." The Weekly Westminster Gazette, 1922 Aug 12 (Box 33, Folder 1302)
      - "The Greatest Speech." The Outline, 1928 Jul 7 (Box 33, Folder 1303)
      - "The Half Century--the Twenties" (radio presentation): typescript, 1950 (Box 33, Folder 1304)
      - "Hands That War." Daily Chronicle, 1916 Feb 17-Jun 3 (Box 33, Folder 1305)
      - "Heil Hamm"
        - Holograph notebooks (possibly mixed drafts; one notebook with essay on Alan Gay, review of Winston Churchill, "The Gathering Storm," and article on "The Difference Between English and American Decmocracy") (Box 34, Folder 1306-10)
        - Revised draft. Holograph notebook, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1311)
      - "Ho! Ho! Ho! Very Odd Law Case" (with essay "Extraordinary Journey"): two holograph notebooks, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1312)
      - "Housing Shortage" (with book reviews and untitled sixty-six page draft): holograph notebook (Box 35, Folder 1313)
      - "How Men Treat Women." John O' London's Weekly, 1928 Apr 21 (Box 35, Folder 1314)
      - "I Believe"
        See: Box 33, folder 1280
      - "Ibstone" (with essay, "What a Stupid Thing to Do"): holograph notebook, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1315)
      - "If I Had to Live My Life Over Again." The Daily Mail, 1928 Aug 18 (Box 35, Folder 1316)
      - "In the Cauldron of Africa" (Parts II-IV). Sunday Times (London), 1960 (Box 35, Folder 1317)
      - "The Inconveniences of Power." Time and Tide (with newspaper advertisement), 1929 Jun 21 (Box 35, Folder 1318)
      - "Inferiority Complex." Woman's Journal, 1928 Sep (Box 35, Folder 1319)
      - "Introduction to 'Polikushka'": printed text, photocopy, [1933] (Box 35, Folder 1320)